<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data analytics on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/data-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data analytics on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 08:19:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/data-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa weather vs. Ottawa JavaScript Meetup attendance: an R analysis</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ottawa-weather-vs-ottawa-javascript-meetup-attendance-an-r-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 08:19:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ottawa-weather-vs-ottawa-javascript-meetup-attendance-an-r-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The more you used it, the more you discover great stuff… I wanted to do some analysis with some weather data, but did not want to start searching and scraping sites, then merging and cleansing…you know the drill. So I came across this neat R package named weatherData. weatherData provides functions that help in fetching weather data from websites, documentation found here -&amp;gt; https://ram-n.github.io/weatherData/.
So I got inspired to compare Ottawa weather and Ottawa JavaScript Meetup attendance!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics with R and SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/data-analytics-r-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 20:04:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/data-analytics-r-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>First Happy New Year and best wishes for 2015!
Yes, Data Analytics with R and SQL Server … As Data and Business Intelligence Architects I personally think we just can’t dismiss or push aside the Data Science “landscape”. Hence that’s why I registered and currently more than half way through the Data Science Specialization on Courserafrom the Johns Hopkins University. Even though I have been working with R for a while I wanted to get some kind of recognition, attestation for my skills and also just because I can 😉</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>