<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>apache spark on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/apache-spark/</link>
    <description>Recent content in apache spark on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:09:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/apache-spark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing NYC Citi Bike data with Azure Databricks</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/analyzing-nyc-citi-bike-data-with-azure-databricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:09:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/analyzing-nyc-citi-bike-data-with-azure-databricks/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since my last post! How about analyzing NYC Citi Bike data with Azure Databricks. Azure Databricks is a fast, easy, and collaborative Apache Spark-based analytics platform. Designed in collaboration with Microsoft and the creators of Apache Spark, Azure Databricks combines the best of Databricks and Azure to help customers accelerate innovation with one-click set up, streamlined workflows and an interactive workspace that enables collaboration between data scientists, data engineers, and business analysts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to SQL Server using Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/connect-sql-server-using-apache-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 11:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/connect-sql-server-using-apache-spark/</guid>
      <description>In-memory distributed processing for large datasets… How to connect to SQL Server using Apache Spark? The Spark documentation covers the basics of the API and Dataframes, there is a lack of info. and examples on actually how to get this feature to work.
  First, what is Apache Spark? Apache Spark is an open source big data processing framework built around speed, ease of use, and sophisticated analytics. A fast and general processing engine compatible with Hadoop data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
