<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Databases on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/categories/databases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Databases on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 08:31:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/categories/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Datascape Podcast - December Cloud Updates</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/datascape-podcast-december-cloud-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 08:31:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/datascape-podcast-december-cloud-updates/</guid>
      <description>I had a great discussion with my friends on the Datascape Podcast to discuss latest cloud updates.
In this episode, Warner (Azure), yours truly -&amp;gt; Stephane (GCP), Pierig (AWS) and Chris discuss several interesting cloud updates released on the public cloud(s) over the last few months.
  Link to episode: Episode 38 - December Cloud Updates
Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datascape Podcast - August Cloud Updates</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/datascape-podcast-august-cloud-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:45:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/datascape-podcast-august-cloud-updates/</guid>
      <description>I sat down with my friends on the Datascape Podcast to discuss latest cloud updates.
In this episode, Warner (Azure), yours truly -&amp;gt; Stephane (GCP), Pierig (AWS) and Chris discuss several interesting cloud updates released on the public cloud(s) over the last few months.
  Link to episode: Episode 36 - August Cloud Updates
Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying single instance SQL Server 2017 on GKE</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/deploying-single-instance-sql-server-2017-on-gke/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:30:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/deploying-single-instance-sql-server-2017-on-gke/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is an open-source container orchestration system for automating deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications. Running a SQL Server database on Kubernetes is a topic of discussion nowadays as Kubernetes provides ways to provision stateful containers using persistent volumes, statefulsets, etc.
The following post is a tutorial we recently published on Google’s Partner Solutions that demonstrates how to provision a single instance of SQL Server 2017 on Linux on GKE using Regional persistent disks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recapping Google Next &#39;19 with Stephane</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/recapping-google-next-2019-with-stephane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 09:30:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/recapping-google-next-2019-with-stephane/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to the Datascape Podcast by my friend and Team lead Chris Presley from Pythian to discuss and recap some of the interesting announcements at Google Next &amp;lsquo;19. Great discussions. I look forward to my next invitation!
  Link to episode: Episode 33 - Recapping Google Next 2019 with Stephane
Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pause Azure SQL Data Warehouse(s) with Azure Automation</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/pause-azure-sql-data-warehouses-with-azure-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 11:19:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/pause-azure-sql-data-warehouses-with-azure-automation/</guid>
      <description>Folks it as been a while… You are knee deep in your Development and Testing activities and you just noticed that you have forgotten to Pause your Azure SQL Data Warehouse(s)… while you were not using it! Thus incurring significant costs towards your next Azure billing cycle. This post will quickly show you how to use Azure Automationand PowerShell in order to remediate this. You may not have access to create an Azure Automation service, but you can share this with your Azure Administrator and/or DevOps Team Lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server HA using Kubernetes in Azure Container Services (AKS)</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 13:40:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</guid>
      <description>In a nutshell, Kubernetesis a container orchestration tool that enables container management at scale. Kubernetes isn’t a replacement for Docker. However, Kubernetes is a replacement for some of the higher-level technologies that have emerged around Docker (i.e Docker Swarm). To learn more about Kubernetes, check out this Getting Started Guide.
Enters Azure Container Service (AKS)which manages your hosted Kubernetes environment, making it quick and easy to deploy and manage containerized applications without container orchestration expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingest real time streaming data for time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ingest-real-time-streaming-data-for-time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 11:59:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ingest-real-time-streaming-data-for-time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how to ingest sample real time streaming data from PubNubto a Postgresdatabase with the TimescaleDBextension installed and enabled for time series analysis. I wrote a small Node.js app to test and demonstrate how TimescaleDB performs well in fetching results while data is also being ingested in the database. Will be using the following data feed, Market Orders– an artificial data stream that provides the latest market orders for a fictitious marketplace and you can clone or download the GitHub repository from -&amp;gt; https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing TimescaleDB on Azure</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/installing-timescaledb-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 16:30:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/installing-timescaledb-azure/</guid>
      <description>Installing TimescaleDB on Azure. First some housekeeping… A time series database is a software system that is optimized for handling time series data, arrays of numbers indexed by time (a datetime or a datetime range). In some fields these time series are called profiles, curves, or traces.
  Lately I discovered TimescaleDB, an open source time-series database engineered up from PostgreSQL and packaged as an extension. It is optimized for fast ingest and complex queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Graph in SQL Server 2017</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-graph-sql-server-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 09:35:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-graph-sql-server-2017/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned several times before… Graphs are everywhere! Graph features are being introduced in SQL Server 2017. Offering graph database capabilities to model many-to-many relationships. The graph relationships are integrated into Transact-SQL and receive the benefits of using SQL Server as the foundational database management system.
What is a graph database? In context, a graph database is a database that uses graph structures for semantic queries with nodes, edges and properties to represent and store data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure and manage SQL Server on Linux</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/configure-manage-sql-server-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 14:42:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/configure-manage-sql-server-linux/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server Configuration Manageris a tool to manage the services associated with SQL Server running on Windows. To configure and manage SQL Server on Linux we use mssql-conf. mssql-conf is a configuration script that installs with SQL Server vNext (Linux). Latest release and documentation available here -&amp;gt; https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/linux/The tool is installed in the following directory path /opt/mssql/bin let’s explore what mssql-conf is all about.
Open a Terminal session and see what type of help and information we get…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running SQL Server on Linux in Docker on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/running-sql-server-linux-docker-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 12:23:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/running-sql-server-linux-docker-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker? Dockeris an open platform for developers and sysadmins to build, ship, and run distributed applications, whether on laptops, data centers, VMs, or in the cloud. Docker allows applications to be isolated into containers with instructions for exactly what they need to survive that can be easily ported from machine to machine. Though Virtual machines also allow the exact same thing, and numerous other tools already exist to make rebuilding these configurations portable and reproducible, Docker has a more simplified structure compared to both of these, the real area where it causes disruption is resource efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server on Linux - What&#39;s installed?</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-linux-whats-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 23:23:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-linux-whats-installed/</guid>
      <description>Software… Are you the curious type like me who needs to know what’s been installed and where it is located on your system!
Exploring the public preview of SQL Server vNext CTP1.1, and installing the following necessary packages mssql-server, mssql-tools, and msodbcsql for running and using SQL Server on Linux. This post is about these packages, finding out what files are installed and where, but before we jump in some minor housekeeping stuff…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing SQL Server on Linux on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/installing-sql-server-linux-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 22:49:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/installing-sql-server-linux-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server vNext represents a major step towards making SQL Server a platform that enables choices of development languages, data types, on-premises and in the cloud, and across operating systems by bringing the power of SQL Server to Linux, Linux-based Docker containers, and Windows.
For all the downloads, code samples and to stay informed visit the following link SQL Server v.Next Public PreviewI am sharing with you my experiences, gotchas in installing SQL Server on Linux on an existing Ubuntu VM I already had running for a while…I have since installed SQL Server for Linux on several other local VM’s and in Azure without any issues just by following the documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to SQL Server using Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/connect-sql-server-using-apache-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 11:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/connect-sql-server-using-apache-spark/</guid>
      <description>In-memory distributed processing for large datasets… How to connect to SQL Server using Apache Spark? The Spark documentation covers the basics of the API and Dataframes, there is a lack of info. and examples on actually how to get this feature to work.
    First, what is Apache Spark? Apache Sparkis an open source big data processing framework built around speed, ease of use, and sophisticated analytics. A fast and general processing engine compatible with Hadoop data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 Row-Level Security</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-2016-row-level-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:47:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-2016-row-level-security/</guid>
      <description>With SQL Server 2016 literately just days away from being officially available to public for download (Get ready, SQL Server 2016 coming on June 1st). I wanted to highlight one important new key future called Row-Level Security. So what is Row Level Security? Row-Level Security enables customers to control access to rows in a database table based on the characteristics of the user executing a query (e.g., group membership or execution context).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 - Dynamic Data Masking</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/anonymize-sensitive-data-dynamic-data-masking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 15:17:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/anonymize-sensitive-data-dynamic-data-masking/</guid>
      <description>With SQL Server 2016 just around the corner, a series of new features and enhancements will be introduced. More specifically some important Security Upgrades; Always Encrypted, Row Level Security, and Dynamic Data Masking. This post covers SQL Server 2016 – Dynamic Data Masking (DDM).
Note: DDM is also available in Azure SQL Database see the following link for details -&amp;gt; http://bit.ly/1eG7Que
  What is Dynamic Data Masking? Dynamic Data Masking enables you to anonymize sensitive data, real-time obfuscation of data to prevent unauthorized access by controlling how the data appears in the output of database queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ContosoRetailDW on Azure SQL Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/contosoretaildw-azure-sql-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 14:58:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/contosoretaildw-azure-sql-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year! It as been a while my friends… here goes 😉
ContosoRetailDW on Azure SQL Data Warehouse This post assumes you are familiar or have already been introduced to Azure SQL Data Warehouse. If not I strongly encourage to read and follow-up on the SQL Data Warehouse Documentationto get you going.
Optionally if you would like to have a local on premise copy of the ContosoRetailDW database – A fictitious retail demo dataset used for presenting Microsoft Business Intelligence products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cloud Services - Neo4j</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/azure-cloud-services-neo4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 09:22:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/azure-cloud-services-neo4j/</guid>
      <description>Yes another exploration and exercise on graph modeling. This time about something I often use… the Cloud: Microsoft Azure. Thought it would be interesting to model the available Azure Cloud Service offerings by category, region, and location. The inspiration and data comes from the following source of information on the following web page http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/regions/#services. A trivial one, but useful for demonstrating and understanding concepts. This is also a great example of how to store master data and discover new insights in existing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo4j: Montreal-Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport (YUL)</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/neo4j-montreal-pierre-elliott-trudeau-international-airport-yul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 19:50:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/neo4j-montreal-pierre-elliott-trudeau-international-airport-yul/</guid>
      <description>A quick exercise on graph modeling. I recently got inspired from one of Nicole White’spost who did something similar with the Dallas Fort Worth Airport (DFW) data. So I decided to create a Neo4j graph database of the shopping places (boutiques, restaurants and services)at the Montreal-Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport (YUL). There isn’t any raw data to download on the site. So I will spare you the details of my scrapping efforts and instead share with you my findings and results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing AdventureWorks data into Neo4j</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/importing-adventureworks-data-into-neo4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 11:45:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/importing-adventureworks-data-into-neo4j/</guid>
      <description>Graphs are everywhere! In my efforts to spread the word and inform SQL Server Professionals about Neo4j and learn how to take a relational database schema and model it as a graph… AdventureWorks was a no-brainer! Let’s explore how to import a subset of the AdventureWorks database from SQL Server (RDBMS) into Neo4j (GraphDB).
But first some prerequisites. You should at least have a basic understanding of what is a property graph modeland have completed the following modeling guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics with R and SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/data-analytics-r-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 20:04:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/data-analytics-r-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>First Happy New Year and best wishes for 2015!
Yes, Data Analytics with R and SQL Server … As Data and Business Intelligence Architects I personally think we just can’t dismiss or push aside the Data Science “landscape”. Hence that’s why I registered and currently more than half way through the Data Science Specialization on Courserafrom the Johns Hopkins University. Even though I have been working with R for a while I wanted to get some kind of recognition, attestation for my skills and also just because I can 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph data modeling and importing the spreadsheet way</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/graph-data-modeling-and-importing-the-spreadsheet-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 14:26:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/graph-data-modeling-and-importing-the-spreadsheet-way/</guid>
      <description>You are new or quite interested in exploring Graph Databases and would like to know how to start modeling and importing data in Neo4j?
There are several ways that could get you started; the neo4j-shell-tools, Load CSV and Batch Importand many more. I strongly recommend reading and exploring the following resources, but to quickly get you started modeling and easily import a small subset of data (&amp;lt;1000 nodes/relationships) the spreadsheet approach is well suited for this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>