<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gcp on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/gcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gcp on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:30:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying single instance SQL Server 2017 on GKE</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/deploying-single-instance-sql-server-2017-on-gke/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:30:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/deploying-single-instance-sql-server-2017-on-gke/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is an open-source container orchestration system for automating deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications. Running a SQL Server database on Kubernetes is a topic of discussion nowadays as Kubernetes provides ways to provision stateful containers using persistent volumes, statefulsets, etc.
The following post is a tutorial we recently published on Google’s Partner Solutions that demonstrates how to provision a single instance of SQL Server 2017 on Linux on GKE using Regional persistent disks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recapping Google Next &#39;19 with Stephane</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/recapping-google-next-2019-with-stephane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 09:30:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/recapping-google-next-2019-with-stephane/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to the Datascape Podcast by my friend and Team lead Chris Presley from Pythian to discuss and recap some of the interesting announcements at Google Next &amp;lsquo;19. Great discussions. I look forward to my next invitation!
  Link to episode: Episode 33 - Recapping Google Next 2019 with Stephane
Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying data to the Cloud from the Command line</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/copying-data-to-the-cloud-from-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 16:46:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/copying-data-to-the-cloud-from-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>Copying data to the Cloud from the Command line, this is what this post is all about. Over the last couple of years we have seen vendors offering different object storage platforms/services in the Cloud. Cloud storage typically refers to a hosted object storage service! The following are considered the most known and used Cloud Object Storage platforms and we are going to demonstrate how to copy data to each from the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>