<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>analytics on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in analytics on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:09:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing NYC Citi Bike data with Azure Databricks</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/analyzing-nyc-citi-bike-data-with-azure-databricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:09:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/analyzing-nyc-citi-bike-data-with-azure-databricks/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been a while since my last post! How about analyzing NYC Citi Bike data with Azure Databricks. Azure Databricks is a fast, easy, and collaborative Apache Spark-based analytics platform. Designed in collaboration with Microsoft and the creators of Apache Spark, Azure Databricks combines the best of Databricks and Azure to help customers accelerate innovation with one-click set up, streamlined workflows and an interactive workspace that enables collaboration between data scientists, data engineers, and business analysts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa weather vs. Ottawa JavaScript Meetup attendance: an R analysis</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ottawa-weather-vs-ottawa-javascript-meetup-attendance-an-r-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 08:19:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ottawa-weather-vs-ottawa-javascript-meetup-attendance-an-r-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The more you used it, the more you discover great stuff&amp;#8230; I wanted to do some analysis with some weather data, but did not want to start searching and scraping sites, then merging and cleansing&amp;#8230;you know the drill. So I came across this neat R package named weatherData. weatherData provides functions that help in fetching weather data from websites, documentation found here -&amp;gt; https://ram-n.github.io/weatherData/.
So I got inspired to compare Ottawa weather and Ottawa JavaScript Meetup attendance!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>