<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 13:40:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server HA using Kubernetes in Azure Container Services (AKS)</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 13:40:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</guid>
      <description>In a nutshell, Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool that enables container management at scale. Kubernetes isn’t a replacement for Docker. However, Kubernetes is a replacement for some of the higher-level technologies that have emerged around Docker (i.e Docker Swarm). To learn more about Kubernetes, check out this Getting Started Guide.
Enters Azure Container Service (AKS) which manages your hosted Kubernetes environment, making it quick and easy to deploy and manage containerized applications without container orchestration expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running SQL Server on Linux in Docker on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/running-sql-server-linux-docker-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 12:23:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/running-sql-server-linux-docker-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker? Docker is an open platform for developers and sysadmins to build, ship, and run distributed applications, whether on laptops, data centers, VMs, or in the cloud. Docker allows applications to be isolated into containers with instructions for exactly what they need to survive that can be easily ported from machine to machine. Though Virtual machines also allow the exact same thing, and numerous other tools already exist to make rebuilding these configurations portable and reproducible, Docker has a more simplified structure compared to both of these, the real area where it causes disruption is resource efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
