<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sql server on linux on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/sql-server-on-linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sql server on linux on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 13:40:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/sql-server-on-linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server HA using Kubernetes in Azure Container Services (AKS)</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 13:40:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</guid>
      <description>In a nutshell, Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool that enables container management at scale. Kubernetes isn’t a replacement for (https://www.docker.com/what-docker)[Docker]. However, Kubernetes is a replacement for some of the higher-level technologies that have emerged around Docker (i.e Docker Swarm). To learn more about Kubernetes, check out this Getting Started Guide.
Enters Azure Container Service (AKS) which manages your hosted Kubernetes environment, making it quick and easy to deploy and manage containerized applications without container orchestration expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure and manage SQL Server on Linux</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/configure-manage-sql-server-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 14:42:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/configure-manage-sql-server-linux/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server Configuration Manageris a tool to manage the services associated with SQL Server running on Windows. To configure and manage SQL Server on Linux we use mssql-conf. mssql-conf is a configuration script that installs with SQL Server vNext (Linux). Latest release and documentation available here -&amp;gt; https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/linux/.
The tool is installed in the following directory path /opt/mssql/bin let’s explore what mssql-conf is all about.
Open a Terminal session and see what type of help and information we get…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running SQL Server on Linux in Docker on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/running-sql-server-linux-docker-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 12:23:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/running-sql-server-linux-docker-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker? Docker is an open platform for developers and sysadmins to build, ship, and run distributed applications, whether on laptops, data centers, VMs, or in the cloud. Docker allows applications to be isolated into containers with instructions for exactly what they need to survive that can be easily ported from machine to machine. Though Virtual machines also allow the exact same thing, and numerous other tools already exist to make rebuilding these configurations portable and reproducible, Docker has a more simplified structure compared to both of these, the real area where it causes disruption is resource efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server on Linux - What&#39;s installed?</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-linux-whats-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 23:23:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-linux-whats-installed/</guid>
      <description>Software… Are you the curious type like me who needs to know what’s been installed and where it is located on your system!
Exploring the public preview of SQL Server vNext CTP1.1, and installing the following necessary packages mssql-server, mssql-tools, and msodbcsql for running and using SQL Server on Linux. This post is about these packages, finding out what files are installed and where, but before we jump in some minor housekeeping stuff…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing SQL Server on Linux on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/installing-sql-server-linux-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 22:49:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/installing-sql-server-linux-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server vNext represents a major step towards making SQL Server a platform that enables choices of development languages, data types, on-premises and in the cloud, and across operating systems by bringing the power of SQL Server to Linux, Linux-based Docker containers, and Windows.
For all the downloads, code samples and to stay informed visit the following link -&amp;gt; SQL Server v.Next Public Preview.
I am sharing with you my experiences, gotchas in installing SQL Server on Linux on an existing Ubuntu VM I already had running for a while…I have since installed SQL Server for Linux on several other local VM’s and in Azure without any issues just by following the documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>