<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Live Streaming on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/live-streaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Live Streaming on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 11:59:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/live-streaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingest real time streaming data for time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ingest-real-time-streaming-data-for-time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 11:59:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/ingest-real-time-streaming-data-for-time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how to ingest sample real time streaming data from PubNub to a Postgres database with the TimescaleDB extension installed and enabled for time series analysis. I wrote a small Node.js app to test and demonstrate how TimescaleDB performs well in fetching results while data is also being ingested in the database. Will be using the following data feed, Market Orders &amp;#8211; an artificial data stream that provides the latest market orders for a fictitious marketplace and you can clone or download the GitHub repository from -&amp;gt; https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time streaming dashboard with Power BI</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/real-time-streaming-dashboard-power-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 15:32:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/real-time-streaming-dashboard-power-bi/</guid>
      <description>I was recently asked to provide a simple demo/proof-of-concept on how to quickly create a real-time streaming dashboard with Power BI. Did you know that you can stream data and update dashboards in real-time? Any visual or dashboard that can be created in Power BI can also be created to display and update real-time data and visuals. The devices and sources of streaming data can be factory sensors, social media sources, service usage metrics, and anything else from which time-sensitive data can be collected or transmitted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>