<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 10:12:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post using Hugo!</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 10:12:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Yes this is my first blog post using Hugo. Finally decided to venture out of my comfort zone and try some new things this year. So done with Wordpress (thank you for all these years), I have decided to import selected posts from my old blog&amp;hellip;
So what to expect? Well basically rants, lessons learned either from the field or from my personnal life, and most importantly about technology, cloud computing and dev stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts, Blogs about Data Engineering, Data Science, ML, and AI</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/podcasts-blogs-about-data-engineering-data-science-ml-and-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 09:21:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/podcasts-blogs-about-data-engineering-data-science-ml-and-ai/</guid>
      <description>Hope you are all enjoying summer? Been asked several times, How do I keep current with technology? What blogs do you read or follow? Which podcasts do you follow and listen to? So I have quickly put together a list of resources, more specifically podcasts, blogs that I consume regularly&amp;#8230; This is no way a definitive list 😉 and in no particular order! Of course these are related to Data Engineering, Data Science, Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for a String in Multiple Files</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/search-string-multiple-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 10:36:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/search-string-multiple-files/</guid>
      <description>In support of an earlier post Fetching NHL Play by Play game data, I was recently asked how could one quickly search for a specific string in multiple JSON files recursively? Well if you are running macOS or Linux grep is your best friend! In a nutshell grep prints lines that contain a match for a pattern. The following is a sample grep and cut command that will list out (output) the games (files) that contains the following string -&amp;gt; &amp;#8220;Montréal Canadiens&amp;#8221;:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>