<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>k8s on Stéphane Fréchette</title>
    <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/k8s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in k8s on Stéphane Fréchette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:30:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephanefrechette.dev/tags/k8s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying single instance SQL Server 2017 on GKE</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/deploying-single-instance-sql-server-2017-on-gke/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:30:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/deploying-single-instance-sql-server-2017-on-gke/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is an open-source container orchestration system for automating deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications. Running a SQL Server database on Kubernetes is a topic of discussion nowadays as Kubernetes provides ways to provision stateful containers using persistent volumes, statefulsets, etc.
The following post is a tutorial we recently published on Google’s Partner Solutions that demonstrates how to provision a single instance of SQL Server 2017 on Linux on GKE using Regional persistent disks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server HA using Kubernetes in Azure Container Services (AKS)</title>
      <link>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 13:40:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephanefrechette.dev/posts/sql-server-ha-using-kubernetes-in-azure-container-services-aks/</guid>
      <description>In a nutshell, Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool that enables container management at scale. Kubernetes isn’t a replacement for Docker. However, Kubernetes is a replacement for some of the higher-level technologies that have emerged around Docker (i.e Docker Swarm). To learn more about Kubernetes, check out this Getting Started Guide.
Enters Azure Container Service (AKS) which manages your hosted Kubernetes environment, making it quick and easy to deploy and manage containerized applications without container orchestration expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>